<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Eric s</title>
    <link>https://esohel30.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Eric s</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://esohel30.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://esohel30.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://esohel30.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coming Soon!</title>
      <link>https://esohel30.github.io/fun-math-problem/project-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esohel30.github.io/fun-math-problem/project-03/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flask-Based Twitter Clone with Live Chatting</title>
      <link>https://esohel30.github.io/projects/project-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esohel30.github.io/projects/project-03/</guid>
      <description>This project is a web-based social media and chat application built using Flask, a Python web framework, and Flask-SocketIO for real-time communications. It provides a platform for users to sign in, create and view tweets, and engage in live chat sessions. The application integrates social media functionalities with real-time chat capabilities to offer a comprehensive user experience.
Key Features User Authentication: Supports user sign-in and sign-up with credential verification and account creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trapping Rain Water</title>
      <link>https://esohel30.github.io/fun-cs-problem/project-03/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esohel30.github.io/fun-cs-problem/project-03/</guid>
      <description>Given n non-negative integers representing an elevation map where the width of each bar is 1, compute how much water it can trap after raining.
Example 1: Input: height = [0,1,0,2,1,0,1,3,2,1,2,1]
Output: 6
Explanation: The above elevation map (black section) is represented by the array [0,1,0,2,1,0,1,3,2,1,2,1]. In this case, 6 units of rainwater (blue section) are being trapped.
Solution in Python class Solution: def trap(self, height: List[int]) -&amp;gt; int: maxright = 0 maxleft = 0 capacity = 0 l, r = 0, len(height) - 1 while l &amp;lt;= r: if maxleft &amp;lt; maxright: amount = maxleft - height[l] if amount &amp;gt; 0: capacity += amount maxleft = max(height[l], maxleft) l += 1 else: amount = maxright - height[r] if amount &amp;gt; 0: capacity += amount maxright = max(maxright, height[r]) r -= 1 return capacity Explanation of Solution</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pac-Dude: A Processing-Based Arcade Game</title>
      <link>https://esohel30.github.io/projects/erpred/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2022 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esohel30.github.io/projects/erpred/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Pac-Dude&amp;rdquo; is a dynamic reimagining of the classic Pac-Man game, developed using the Processing language. This project not only offers a nostalgic arcade experience but also incorporates advanced programming concepts, including sophisticated pathfinding algorithms and state management for the ghost characters.
Key Features Enhanced Gameplay Mechanics: Combines traditional Pac-Man gameplay with new challenges and dynamic difficulty scaling. Custom Map Generation: Algorithmically generated maps provide a unique experience in each game session.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Musically - A Music Analysis Application for Song Lovers!</title>
      <link>https://esohel30.github.io/projects/project-01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 23:15:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esohel30.github.io/projects/project-01/</guid>
      <description>This web application, designed for music lovers, integrates various functionalities including user authentication, music data access through the Spotify API, and a unique feature for lyric generation using Markov chains.
Features User Authentication Login/Signup: Users can create an account or log in to access personalized features. Logout: Session-based logout functionality for security. Profile Management: Options for users to view and edit their profile, including password changes. Music Data Integration Spotify API Usage: Fetches data from Spotify for artist and song information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My 1st post</title>
      <link>https://esohel30.github.io/page/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 11:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esohel30.github.io/page/</guid>
      <description>Desc Text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://esohel30.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://esohel30.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hey! I&amp;rsquo;m Eric. I&amp;rsquo;m currently a freshman at Stony Brook University studying Computer Science and Applied Mathematics.
Things I like: puns puzzles plants mammals Things I don&amp;rsquo;t like: cephalopods mushroom camel-case socks Things that occupy my time: derping teaching tricks to my rabbits trying to understand the world While you&amp;rsquo;re here, feel free to check out my projects. I am also very into competitive programming and math so check out the math and cs pages for fun problems I solved.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
